History's most unlikely friendship.
Victoria & Abdul is a drama, history film directed by Stephen Frears.
Queen Victoria strikes up an unlikely friendship with a
young Indian clerk named Abdul Karim.
Queen Victoria, played by Judi Dench.
Abdul Karim, played by Ali Fazal.
Sir Henry Ponsonby, played by Tim Pigott-Smith.
Bertie, Prince of Wales, played by Eddie Izzard.
Mohammed, played by Adeel Akhtar.
Lord Salisbury, played by Michael Gambon.
Victoria & Abdul is a 2017 biographical historical drama film
directed by Stephen Frears and written by Lee Hall.
The film is based on the book Victoria & Abdul: The True Story of the Queen's Closest Confidant by Shrabani Basu, about the
real-life relationship between Queen Victoria of the United Kingdom and her Indian Muslim servant Abdul Karim.
It stars Judi Dench, Ali Fazal, Michael Gambon, Eddie Izzard, Tim
Pigott-Smith (in his final film role), and Adeel Akhtar.
The film had its world premiere at the 74th Venice Film Festival and was
theatrically released on 15 September 2017 in the United Kingdom.
It grossed $66.6 million worldwide.
The film was nominated for Best Costume Design and Best Makeup and Hairstyling at the 90th Academy Awards, and
Best Actress in a Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy (for Dench) at the 75th Golden Globe Awards.
The film has been criticised for emphasising the greatness of the
British Empire, and also for social engineering.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, biography,
based on true story, 19th century, british monarchy.
The tone is emotional.